Jessica YI FEI **Bo**

Boston, US | Zurich, CH | Vancouver, CA

jessica7bo@gmail.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/jessica-bo/

https://jessica-bo.github.io/

Researcher, engineer, and designer with multidisciplinary experiences in robotics, software engineering, medical device development, and mixed reality. My research interests broadly intersect with human-centered design of intelligent systems. I am currently working on algorithms and HCI related to digital medicine at MIT.

EDUCATION



ETH Zurich | MSc Mechanical Engineering, concentration in Robotics

Expected Spring 2023



Thesis (at MIT): TBD

Semester Project: Worldloop Transfer – evaluating perceptual capabilities learned through embodied tasks Coursework: Probabilistic Artificial Intelligence, 3D Vision, Human Factors, Mixed Reality, Computer Vision



University of British Columbia | BASc Mechanical Engineering, with distinction

2020

<u>Thesis</u>: Wheelchair detection and state estimation using laser scanning sensors for mobile robots Coursework: Machine Learning, Algorithms, Data Structures, Mechanical Design, Instrumentation

EXPERIENCES

Traverso Lab, MIT | Advisors: Giovanni Traverso, Hen-Wei Huang, Peter Chai **Visiting Scholar for Master Thesis**

Full Year 2022

Python, sensors, bioethics

- Developing mitigation strategies for data distribution shift of deep learning models used in clinical applications
- Evaluating patient acceptability and bioethics of closed-loop drug delivery systems with diagnostic abilities

Visual Intelligence and Learning Lab, EPFL| Advisors: Amir Zamir

Summer – Fall 2021

Summer@EPFL Research Intern

Python, PyTorch, Habitat

- · Investigated perceptual capabilities developed by reinforcement learning agents trained on embodied tasks
- Developed transfer learning framework to evaluate active perception modules on downstream vision tasks

Attentiv Medical | Advisors: Konrad Walus, Manon Ranger

Fall 2019 - Fall 2021

Co-Founder and Research Lead

Python, scikit-learn, sensors

- Designed a patentable bioelectric sensor and real-time monitoring system for detecting IV infiltration
- Led 80+ user and expert interviews to determine engineering, regulatory, and clinical design requirements Awards: James Dyson National Winner (\$3k) and International Top 20, Microsoft Discover AI – Healthcare Winner (\$6k), Medical Device Design Center – Principal Award (\$5k), UBC Innovation on Board Start-Up Competition Runner Up (\$2.5k), New Venture Design Best Project (\$800), New Venture Design Industry Award (\$600), RBC Get Seeded Winner (\$500)

CARIS Robotics Lab, UBC | Advisor: Machiel Van der Loos

Fall 2019 – Spring 2020

Bachelor Thesis

ROS, Python, MATLAB, scikit-learn, TensorFlow

- Proposed a wheelchair state estimation algorithm to improve safety in interactions with mobile robots
- Used a multi-class neural network to predict wheelchair orientation from 2D laser data with 86% accuracy

Coursera | Team: Payments Engineering, Decision Science

Summer 2020

Software Engineering Intern

Scala, Python, SQL

- Led the backend consolidation of billing information for 6.5M+ monthly transactions in a RESTful API
- Analyzed 900+ A/B experiments and causally identified patterns in statistically significant revenue patterns

Amazon | Team: Amazon Marketplace

Summer 2019

Software Engineering Intern

Java, Spring, AWS (SNS, SQS, Lambda)

- Designed a backend pipeline using AWS services to guarantee real-time event polling and delivery
- Implemented an event-processing service in Java for 120k+ annual Amazon membership events

Blackberry QNX (Autonomous Vehicle Innovation Centre) | Advisor: Gordon Bell

Fall 2018

Autonomous Vehicle R&D Intern

C, MATLAB, QNX, LIDAR

- Developed a LiDAR processing algorithm that detects road signs and free space with < 10 ms runtime
- Applied projective geometry to 3D LiDAR point cloud to fuse with 2D camera image for visualization at CES

CERTEC Group, Lund University | Advisor: Héctor Caltenco

Research Assistant

Arduino, sensors, fabrication, user testing

- Prototyped a hand spasticity rehabilitation device that provides stimulating motion-triggered feedback
- Integrated real-time control of a computer keyboard using hand movements with accelerometers and Arduino

PUBLICATIONS

Papers

Bo, J, Ta, K, Nishida, R, Yeh, G, Tsang, V, Bolton, M, Ranger, M, Walus, K (2022). ATTENTIV: Instrumented Peripheral Catheter for the Detection of Catheter Dislodgement in IV Infiltration. *44th Annual International Conference on the IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society (EMBC*).

Agrawal, D, Lobsiger, J, **Bo, J**, Kaufmann, V, Armeni, I (2022). HoloLabel: Augmented Reality User-In-The-Loop Online Annotation Tool for As-Is Building Information. *European Conference on Computing in Construction*.

Vinker, Y, Pajouheshgar, E, **Bo, J**, Bachmann, R, Bermano, AH, Cohen-Or, D, Zamir, A, Shamir, A (2022). CLIPasso: Semantically Aware Object Sketching. *ACM Transactions on Graphics (SIGGRAPH)*. [paper]

Bo, JY, Van der Loos, HFM (2021). Detection of Wheelchair Orientation in Human-Robot Interactions. *International Conference BIOMDLORE*. [paper]

Abstracts

Bo, J (2020). Detection of Wheelchairs Using Laser Scanning Sensors for Mobile Robotics. *Multidisciplinary Undergraduates Research Conference.* (Best Oral Presentation)

Gwara, M, Tsang, VL, Thompson, CA, Smith, S, **Bo, J**, Fletcher, S, Janusz, N, Chew, SY, Janusz, M, Thompson, CK, Bertrand, M, Woods, H, Thompson, C (2017). Use of Centralized Electronic Medical Records System in Paediatric Care. *American Academy of Pediatrics*.

AWARDS

2022	Swiss-European Mobility Scholarship (4500 SFr.) – Swiss-European Mobility Programme
2021	Heyning-Roelli Mobility Grant (1100 SFr.) – Heyning-Roelli Foundation
2021	EPFL Summer Research Fellowship (4800 SFr.) – École polytechnique fédérale de Lausanne
2020	Order of the White Rose Scholarship Finalist – Nominated by UBC Applied Science
2020	Top 5% Academic Ranking – UBC Applied Science and Mechanical Engineering
2020	Canada Graduate Scholarships-Master's (\$17,500 CAD, declined) – NSERC Canada
2019	Speak Out for Engineering Americas (1st Place, £300) – Institution of Mechanical Engineers
2019	Women in Technology Scholarship (\$10,000 CAD) – IKB BC Scholarship Society
2017	Go Global Research Abroad Programs Award (\$2000 CAD) – University of British Columbia
2016	NSERC Experience Award (\$4500 CAD) — NSERC Canada
All years	UBC Dean's Honour List – University of British Columbia

ADVISORY & MENTORSHIP

Open Roboethics | Competition & Toolkit Team

2021 - Present

2020 - Present

- Volunteer for organizing AI ethics competitions and developing a public-use ethical AI toolkit
- connect-f, UBC | STEM Mentor

Mentoring high school students in exploring an education and career in engineering and computer science

International Children's Advisory Network (iCAN) | Conference Committee Chair

2016 – 2019

- Led a 10+ member international team to plan events and fundraisers for the annual iCAN Summits
- Reviewed and improved upon European Medicine Agency's pediatrics clinical research policies
- Kidscan Youth Advisory Council | Youth Advisor & Mentor

2014 - 2019

- Advised 10+ Vancouver research teams on promoting youth involvement in pediatrics research
- Reviewed Canada-wide policies for standardizing clinical pediatrics research consent/assent protocol

SKILLS

Languages: Python (PyTorch, Tensorflow, scikit-learn, NumPy, pandas, matplotlib), Java, Scala, C, MATLAB, SQL Computer: ROS. QNX. Linux. Unity. Blender. HoloLens. AWS

Engineering: SolidWorks, Fusion360, ANSYS, Arduino, 3D printing, soldering, instrumentation